Guide to the David Patrick McIntosh papers,1965-1989.
McIntosh, David Patrick papers,1965-1989.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
David Patrick McIntosh papers, 1965-1989.
7562
David McIntosh, 1950-1989.
3.5 cubic ft.
Audio tapes, correspondence, journals, poetry, songs, fiction, plays.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, journals, poetry, songs, fiction, and plays by David McIntosh. Includes audio tapes of his short opera, Can.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
David Patrick McIntosh was born in Philadelphia and grew up in Omaha, Nebraska, where he attended a Jesuit school. He later moved to Tennessee, where worked with an alternative theater company in Knoxville, The Play Group, from 1974-1979, and then moved to New York City. In New York he wrote and worked both in the theatre and at the New York City Gay and Lesbian Center where he designed an ornamental garden. He died from complications of AIDS in 1989.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, journals, poetry, songs, fiction, and plays by David McIntosh. Includes audio tapes of his short opera, Can.
SUBJECTS
Names:
McIntosh, David, 1950-1989.; New York City Gay and Lesbian Center.; Play Group (Knoxville, Tenn.)
Subjects:
Gay men.; Gay men's writings.; Experimental theater--New York (State)--New York.; Gardens--Design.; Gay liberation movement--New York (State)--New York.; Dramatists.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Collecting program: Human Sexuality Collection.
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence and writings
  - McIntosh's Garden at the Gay and Lesbian Center, NYC (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Kira Letters (Correspondence from Kira Gale, 1980 ) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Kira Letters (Correspondence from Kira Gale, 1981 ) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Kira Letters (Correspondence from Kira Gale, 1981 ) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Kira Letters (Correspondence from Kira Gale, 1982 ) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Kira Letters (Correspondence from Kira Gale, 1983 ) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Kira Letters (Correspondence from Kira Gale, 1986 ) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - CAN Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - CAN Correspodnence (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1979-1983 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letters, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letters (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Letters to Mr. Haber, David's Psychiatrist, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Letters to Chuck, (Charles Scriber?) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Fishing at Fort Walker and Three Other Plays (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - The Piper Man (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - The Piper Man (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - The Piper Man (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Leoner (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Mama's Boy (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Hello! (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Hello! (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Lacie (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Lacie (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Lacie (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Martha (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Martha (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - The T-Rific Two (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Evangeline (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Evangeline (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 200 RPM (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - The Poplar Patch (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Adam (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Okuni (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Okuni (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - CAN (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Althea (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Fiction (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Dr. Brody (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - First Hand (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - October (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Mortal Love (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Self-Portrait in Jan. 1978 and Miscellaneous Writings (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Poetry Drafts (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Alternate Roots (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Miscellaneous, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Miscellaneous Ideas (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Miscellaneous Buisness (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Miscellaneous Writing (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - David McIntosh's Biography by David Rain, Memorial Eulogies (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1986-1989 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Letters, ca. 1988 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Jack Eric Williams (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Letters to Jack Eric Williams (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Letters to Jack Eric Williams (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Reviews for the Play Group Productions (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Garden Design (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Photographs of McIntosh, Family and Friends (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - McIntosh's Death Certificate and Obituary (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Missing Lissie, Summer, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Poetry Drafts (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Poetry Drafts (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Poems (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Poems - Knoxville, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - A Knoxville Book, McIntosh's Published Book of Poetry, 1977 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Poems from Summer 1988 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Poetry Drafts (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Poetry Drafts (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Poetry Drafts (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Poetry Drafts (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Poetry Drafts (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Poetry Drafts (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Creations (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Creations (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Creations (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Creations (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Poetry Drafts (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Poetry Drafts (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous Writing (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous Writing (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous Writing (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Journals and scrapbooks
  - Nov. 16, 1965 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Oct. 10, 1968; Oct. 30, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Oct. 17, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - 1970? (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Early 1970's? (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Jan. 1970 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Feb. 1970 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Feb. 1970 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Feb. 1970 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Feb. 25, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Apr. 1970 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - July 1970 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Sept. 1970 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - May 1, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Mar. 16, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Aug. 20, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Oct. 1974 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Knoxville, Jan. 1976 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - June 2, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Nov. 10, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Jan. 1978 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - June 14, 1979 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Thanksgiving, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Nov. 29, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Jan. 26, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Apr. 17, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Sept. 2, 1985 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - n.d. (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - n.d. (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - n.d. (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Audiocassettes
  - "Christmas Songs for Queers," tape 1, 6791
  - "Christmas Songs for Queers," tape 2, 6792
  - "Christmas Songs for Queers," 1979, Side A, 6793a
  - "Christmas Songs for Queers," 1979, Side A, 6793a
  - "David McIntosh Piano/Songs: 'This Gown,' 'Grasshopper Song,'" Side B
  - "Interview with a Doctor on AIDS", 6794a
  - "McIntosh/Young: Piano, Vocals", 6795a
  - "Can," David McIntosh's Short Opera, 6796a
  - "David McIntosh Piano/Songs", 6797a